# **Hector Torres**

hectorite@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

# **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

Ruby | Rails | Javascript | React | MySQL

# **SUMMARY**

I'm a Full-stack developer with 2+ years of professional experience in multiple technologies including React, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Tailwind, HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. They also have experience in pair programming and working within an agile development methodology. Additionally, they have experience in developing mobile applications.

# **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Vue.js, Next.js

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, C#, solidity, jQuery, NodeJS
Tools: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, RSpec, Chrome Dev Tools
Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

## **EXPERIENCE**

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

#### Full-stack Web Development Student & Mentor

January 2022 - Present

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building multiple full-stack projects both independently and via pair-programming

Bytecar – This web page lets you make an appointment for an electric car test drive. API

Built with: React, Tailwind, Redux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

My Recipe — An app that keeps track of all your recipes, ingredients, and inventory. demo

Built with: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, RSpec, PostgreSQL, Devise, Tailwind

My Finance — A Finance app to organize and keep track of your expenses. demo.

Built with: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Tailwind, Devise, and PostgreSQL.

MICROVERSE Remote

## Mentor (Volunteer)

March 2022 - present

- Mentoring junior web developers, by providing technical support through code reviews
- Proposing improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance
- Providing advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program

**INAIPI** 

Santo Domingo, República Dominicana

#### Full-stack developer

November 2019 – March 2022

- Used technologies from C#, HTML5, CSS3, MySQL to develop responsive web applications
- Developed mobile multi-platform apps for both ios and android using Flutter and Kotlin

## **EDUCATION**

**MICROVERSE** 

January 2022 - November 2022

## Remote Full-stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- A full-time program that required work across time zones while pair programming with other software engineers worldwide.
- Leveraged Agile methodologies requiring excellent communication skills to share project status updates, plan daily workflow, create solid documentation, and attend daily standups.
- Used and taught mentees industry-standard git-flow.
- Coding projects included front-end, back-end, and full-stack projects using Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, HTML, and CSS -- and included unit testing when applicable.